# JOSHUA ROCHOTTE, MI, A-CSPO

Phone: (732) 406-1929 • joshjrochotte@gmail.com • LinkedIn.com/in/joshrochotte

#### PERSONAL STATEMENT

A dedicated and passionate product manager serving the life sciences industry for the past 4 years. Experience in leading teams to deliver highly functional, data science focused SAAS products. Looking to secure a role in product focused data analysis or product management

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey**

May 2018

Master of Information, Data Science | Technology, Information and Management

• Beta Phi Mu Honors

# **Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey**

Dec 2017

Mini-MBA, Biopharma Innovation

# **Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey**

May 2017

Bachelor of Arts, Psychology | Bachelor of Arts Information Technology and Informatics

• Specialization in Game Design and Innovation

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Medidata Solutions: Product Manager, Digital Oversight

Mar 2021 to Present

Execution of program priorities for Virtual Monitoring and Data Science

## Medidata Solutions: Product Owner, RBQM

Apr 2020 to Mar 2021

- Lead teams in development of Microservice Analytics, Metrics Configuration and Data Review solutions
- Passionate Encore Award received Jan 2021 for Exemplified focus on company ideals

## **Medidata Solutions: Implementation Consultant**

Jul 2017 to Apr 2020

• Implementation of Medidata Clinical Cloud Software, study design, consultation, training and data focused error resolution to drive customer success

# TNT IP LLC: Test Engineer

Oct 2016 to Mar 2017

• Research support on consumer electronics and summarization of findings

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Rutgers University, School of Communication and Information Behavioral Informatics Lab Professor Singh

2017

• Influenced Cooperation in Competitive Social Situations Project (Unpublished)

# Gold Group Enterprises, Asbury Park, NJ 2016 Research Assistant • Documentation and research on mobile behavior and health intervention • industry interviews, project design and application prototyping Rutgers University, School of Communication and Information 2016 **EPIK Project** Professor Weber • Document coder for EPIK research project TEACHING EXPERIENCE Rutgers University, School of Communication and Information. Jan 2018 to May 2018 **Teaching Assistant**, Retrieving and Evaluating 04:547:220 • Grading and instructional support, office hours and 1 on 1 tutoring Rutgers University, School of Communication and Information Jan 2017 to Dec 2017 Teaching Assistant, OOP 04:547:202, 3 Sections

**Rutgers University**, School of Communication and Information. Jan 2017 to May 2017 **Teaching Assistant**, IP3 04:547:400

Grading and instructional support, office hours and 1 on 1 tutoring

• Grading and instructional support, office hours and 1 on 1 tutoring and course material development

# PRESENTATIONS AND INVITED LECTURES

"Preparing for ICH E6 (R3) Good Clinical Practice Changes" Xtalks	Jun 2021
"Medidata Cloud Powers Clinical Trials of the Future" US FDA	Aug 2020
"Big Data and Healthcare" Rutgers University	Apr 2018
PROFESSIONAL TRAINING	
Product Management Certificate, Product School	Sep 2021
Google Data Analytics Certificate, Coursera	Aug 2021
A-CSPO Certification, Scrum Alliance	Apr 2021
CSPO Certification, Scrum Alliance	Mar 2020

### **PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS**

New York Academy of Sciences	Jul 2021 to Present
AIPMM	Apr 2021 to Present
RUSCIAA	Jan 2021 to Present
Beta Phi Mu, Omicron Chapter	Apr 2020 to Present
Scrum Alliance	Mar 2020 to Present
PhUSE	Jan 2019 to Present
Project Management Institute	Jan 2018 to Present

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS AND EXPERIENCE

**Programming**: Python, R, SQL, Java, C#, HTML/CSS/JS

**Applications**: Microsoft Office 365, Axure, IndigoDesign, Balsamiq, JustInMind, JIRA, Confluence, Lucidchart, AHA, Draw.IO, AWS, Slack, Salesforce, Trello

**Skills**: Advanced Data Analytics, Business Intelligence, Agile Development, UI/UX Design, Project Management, Workflow Design, Research and Information Management, Risk Based Quality Management, Product Roadmaps, Relationship Management, Database Management

#### **OTHER**

Data Science Passion Projects Computer and Console Gamer Avid Popular Science Reader Classically Trained Vocalist Amateur Cook

#### REFERENCES

# **Available upon Request**